嗨
Hey
你弄错了
You got this all thing wrong
只有摇滚明星才会迟到
just rock star's supposed to be late
摇滚明星的摄影师可不应该
not the rock star photographer
抱歉 孕妇晨疾病 来摸摸肚子
sorry,it's morning sickness, touch the belly
第一次有人让我这么做
It's first time I am being asked
来吧 会带来好运气
come on, it's good luck
打开背景后面的放射灯
Hit the kinos behind the drop.
你觉得怎么样?
So what do you think?
我想人们不会明白的
Uh,I think people aren't gonna get it.
哦 别这样
Oh,come on.
"全美反对" ,(摇滚乐团)
All-american rejects.
将经典美国文化和,代表现代流行文化的你并列
Juxtaposing a classic image of americana,with modern pop culture,you.
是啊 人人都爱合适的对比
Oh,yeah,,everyone loves a good juxtaposition.
我的粉丝都是生于九十年代的
My fans were born in the '90s.
知道吗 你拍了这张照,就会赢得四十多岁的粉丝
You know what? You do this picture,,you'll gain 40 years fans.
- 真的?,- 肯定
- Yeah?,- Yeah.
喜欢Rockwell的东西,(Rockwell 插图画家 描绘传统美国生活)
Love the rockwell thing.
我也这么想
I thought so.
好吧 关掉房里的灯 我们开始
Okay,kill the house lights,,let's go.
等一下
Hang on.
嘿 谁负责布景?
Hey,who's in charge of the backdrop?
- Naomi?,- 什么事?
- Naomi?,- Yeah?
它有什么问题吗?
What's wrong with it?
单词完全是混乱的
Well,the words are completely jumbled.
怎么了?
What?
- 你能读懂那个?,- 当然
- You can read that?,- Of course.
你还好吧?
You okay?
不 上帝
No.Oh,god.
我--我可能正,助记法是什么来着?
I--I could be having a--a--,what's--what's the mnemonic?
F表示脸蛋
Uh...F...f is for face.
我的笑是不是扭曲的?
Is my smile crooked?
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
A代表胳膊
A...a is for arms.Arms...
你该坐下
You should really sit down.
谁能帮她拿点水?
Can somebody get her some water?
S是讲话
S is...s is speech.
我口齿清楚吗?
I'm slurring...
我是不是口齿不清了?
I'm slurring? Huh?
f-a-s-t 快速
oh,f-a-s-T.
T是时间
T is time.
快 谁来...
Hurry,somebody,uh...
打911 告诉他们我中风了!
call 911,,tell them I'm having a stroke!
第三季 第17集,"胎儿的地位"; "Fetal Position"
House,Season 03 Episode 17
嗨 我是House医生
Hi,I'm Dr. House.
我老板说你是个重要人物
My boss says you're important.
把Scarlett Johansson拍得美 有什么难?,(主演 )
Personally, I don't get what's so hard,about making scarlett johansson look pretty.
把胳膊伸到前面来
Arms out in front of you.
手掌向上 就像你正端着批萨
Your palms up,,like you're holding a pizza.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
这么容易 你该考虑换个职业了
It's so easy,,you should consider a career change.
说不定挣更多钱呢
Probably make a lot more money.
Mackman医生告诉你血块清干净了?
Dr. Mackman tell you the clot was clear?
是的
Yes.
他还说你和胎儿都没事
And he said that you and the fetus are fine.
没错
Yeah.
他没提你的旋前肌滑移
He didn't mention your pronator drift.
那意味着什么?
What's that mean?
意味着Mackman是个傻瓜
It means mackman is an idiot.
我能坐下吗?
May I?
当然
Yeah.
那么
So.
你给一个人拍数千张照片
You take thousands of photos of someone,
只要有一张好看就行了
but only one has to look good.
和我这行似乎正好相反
Kind a the opposite of my business.
这和好看没有关系
It's not about looking good.
人们总是隐瞒什么
People are always hiding things.
我不停地拍 直到看清他们的内在
I just keep shooting until,I can see what's really inside them.
我的眼睛还好吗?
My eyes okay?
眼睛非常迷人
Eyes are gorgeous.
血管就没那么迷人
Vessels don't look so hot.
微动脉瘤意味着还会中风
Micro aneurysms predict further strokes.
中风还会发生?
This is gonna happen again?
除非我能找出根本原因
Unless I can figure out,the underlying cause.
鼓起脸颊
Puff up your cheeks.
你应该能不松气的
You should be able to,keep the air in.
说明嘴周围肌肉软弱
It means there's weakness,around the mouth.
你从哪儿学的自己诊断中风?
So where'd you learn,to self-diagnose a stroke?
我孩子的血缘父亲是个神经学家
Oh,my,uh,baby's biological father,is a neurologist.
他曾经说快速记忆法有一天会救我的命 所以...
He once told me the fast mnemonic,could save my life one day,so...
有趣的昵称
interesting pet name.
大部分人用 "老公" 或 "小可爱" .
Most people go with,"husband" or "pookie" .
他是同性恋
He's gay.
精子捐赠者
Just a sperm donor.
当你--
So when you--
在某晚 你把他变成异性恋?
you turned him for a night?
只爱异性一回?
Just straight for one date?
好吧
Okay.
他拿了本杂志和一个杯子 进我的浴室
He took a magazine,and a cup into my bathroom.
真和我情投意合
Man after my own heart.
显然杂志不一样
Different magazine,obviously.
我要撤销Mackman发的出院通知
I'm rescinding mackman's discharge order.
我的下属等会来做些检查,再抽些血
My lackeys will be in to do some tests,,take some more blood,
倒空你的尿液收集袋
and empty your catheter bag.
这不会是你珍爱的时刻
Not a moment you'll want to cherish.
这张绝对与众不同
This is definitely different.
看起来就像...
it looks almost like...
他富有同情心
he's caring.
在病人的档案里还找到别的了吗?
Find anything else,in the patient's folder?
比如诊断?
Like a diagnosis?
尿检里有过量蛋白和红细胞
Urinalysis revealed excessive protein,and red blood cells.
生化检查表明肌酸酐水平超过2.5
Chem panel showed a creatinine level,over 2.5,so.
先是中风 现在肾脏衰竭--为什么?
First she strokes,now her kidneys,are shutting down--why?
超声波没有检查到肿瘤或结石
Ultrasound showed,no tumors or stones,
没有胎儿窘迫的迹象,没有尿道堵塞
no signs of fetal distress,,no urinary tract obstructions.
血压正常 没有惊厥前兆
Bp is fine,no preeclampsia.
谁去过加拉巴哥群岛?,(位于南美 盛产象龟)
Any of you guys,ever been to the galapagos?
病人去过么?
Was our patient there?
登革热 鸡痘 西尼罗河病
Dengue fever,avian pox,even west nile.
不 我在找度假的地方
No,I'm looking for a vacation spot.
就是说我们会有假期?
That mean we get vacation?
你们现在的状态和度假有什么区别?
How would that differ from,your current status?
你准备干什么 放松?
you're gonna do what,relax?
拜访家人
Visiting family.
我叔叔是巨型海龟
My uncle's a giant turtle.
如果是肾脏先衰竭呢?
What if the kidney failure came first?
肾脏也可以引发中风 而不像刚才说的那样
Kidneys could've caused the stroke,,not the other way around.
肾脏通常不会堵住大脑
Kidneys don't often get stuck,in the brain.
我是说它造成了一个血栓
I'm saying it threw a clot.
肾脏衰竭的早期症状是恶心,呕吐 脚踝肿胀
Early symptoms of kidney failure,are nausea, vomiting,ankle swelling.
她可能错当成晨疾病了
She could've mistaken it,for morning sickness.
心脏比肾脏更可能产生血栓
Heart's way more likely to,throw a clot than the kidney.
心音正常
Echo was normal.
病史里没有心脏问题
History indicates no sign,of cardiac problems.
没有 但如果仔细读过病史的话
No,but if one were to read,the history closely,
一定会注意到她六次感染链锁状球菌
one would notice that,she had six cases of strep.
在喉咙 那可是心脏上方十英寸的地方
in her throat. That's the one,about ten inches above the heart.
让我换种说法
Let me rephrase.
六例没根治的链锁状球菌
Six cases of untreated strep.
都给她开了抗生素
She was prescribed antibiotics.
没人把药都吃了
No one takes them all.
他们一旦感觉好了 就停药
They stop when they start feeling better.
所有链锁状球菌都没被根治
All strep is untreated strep.
要是链锁状球菌没治疗 会怎样?
What happens when strep goes untreated?
会导致风湿性发热
It leads to rheumatic fever.
那又会导致...Cameron?
Which leads to...cameron?
二尖瓣狭窄
Mitral valve stenosis.
那会使...肾脏的瓣膜变厚?
Which is a thickening,in the valve of the...kidney?
不 肾脏可没有二尖瓣
No. Kidney doesn't have a mitral valve.
我们会检查她的心脏
We'll go look at the heart.
很好找的
It'll be easy to find.
就是喉咙下方十英寸的红色大泵
It's the big red pumping thing about,ten inches below her throat.
刚才很奇怪
That was weird.
他刚才和平时一样
He was the way he always is.
所以才奇怪
Which is weird.
千万别动 emma
Very still,emma.
- 不好意思,- 没关系
- Sorry.,- No problem.
他撞见你手放在我衬衣上
He caught us with your hand up my shirt.
他对此应该有反应
He's gotta have a reaction to that.
你觉得他度假就是为了这个?
You think that's what the vacation is?
是 失去你的痛苦逼得他待不下去了
Yes. The pain of losing you,is obviously forcing him away.
冠状截面看来正常
coronal slice appears normal.
House没理由放过这事的
There's no way house,just lets this slide.
他肯定在计划什么
He's gotta be planning something.
也许他只是不在乎
Maybe he just doesn't give a crap.
横截面也没问题
Sagittal slice is clean.
你觉得他是误打误撞进那个储藏室的?
You think he just stumbled,into that closet?
他知道我们在那儿,他希望我们知道他察觉了
He knew we were there,,and he wanted us to know that he knew.
或许你本就希望他知道 现在他知道了
Or you wanted him to know,,now he does,
你觉得烦恼是因为他不在乎
and you're annoyed,because he doesn't care.
就在那儿
Right there.
纵截面 钙化的二尖瓣
Transaxial slice,,calcified mitral valve.
几乎看不出来,还没大到造成血栓
Barely.,That's n big enough to throw a clot.
很显然足够大了 因为它已经造成了
Obviously it is,because it did.
House是对的
House was right.
你心脏的一个瓣膜变狭窄了
A valve in your heart is narrowed.
造成血栓 引起中风
It caused the clot,which led to your stroke,
循环的减少引起肾脏问题
and the reduced circulation,caused the problems with your kidneys.
这能治好?
And this'll fix it?
气囊会迫使瓣膜重新打开
The balloon will force the valve back open.
你就好了
And you'll be fine.
做手术我能不用麻醉吗?
can I do this without a sedative?
麻醉非常温和 对胎儿没有风险
It's very mild,,there really is no risk to the fetus.
我们会单独监控孩子的心率
we'll monitor,your baby's heart rate separately.
不会让心率低到危险水平的
We won't allow it to decrease,anywhere near dangerous levels.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你和孩子都会没事的
You're both gonna be fine.
开始吧 Cameron医生
Go ahead,dr. Cameron.
听那心跳
Listen to that heartbeat.
听起来那么...
It sounds so...
开始插管
start threading the catheter.
我不想在法兰克福 台北 新加坡,或者伦敦 安大略换机
No,I don't want a layover in frankfurt,,taipei,singapore,or london,ontario.
我要直飞金边 (柬埔寨)
That's why I asked for a direct flight,to phnom penh.
不降落换机有多难?
How hard is it to not land?
我怎么回答有关系吗?
Does it matter what I answer?
那就好 我很高兴不挂断,有什么新情况?
Then fine,I'd be delighted to hold.,What's new?
你能叫cuddy别来干涉吗?
Can you tell cuddy to stop interfering?
这是她的工作,有什么新情况?
It's her job. What's new?
好消息是emma的心脏已经治好了
Good news is emma's heart is fixed.
坏消息是有其他潜在问题
Bad news is it's not her underlying problem.
她的肾脏还在衰竭
Her kidney'sare still failing.
你要去柬埔寨度假?
you're vacationing in cambodia?
你准备去杀人场放松?,(红色高棉统治时的屠宰场)
You gonna unwind in the killing fields?
不 去给自己抓这么大的鱼
Nope,gonna catch me a fish this big.
湄公巨鲶 超过600磅
Mekong giant catfish,,weighs over 600 pounds.
那些巨鲶不是都快绝种了么?
Aren't those catfish critically endangered?
所以这是我去抓一条的最后机会了
That's why it's my last chance,to catch one.
所有的接线员都...
All of our operators are...
如果二尖瓣已经修复了
if the mitral valve had been properly fixed,
肾脏也该开始好了
the kidney should be getting better.
结论只能是手术做砸了
Which leads us to the conclusion,that you screwed up the procedure.
或者是你诊断错了
Or you screwed up the diagnosis.
冠状瓣膜变厚根本不明显
The mitral valve thickening,was so insignificant,
也许不是造成肾脏衰竭和中风的原因
it probably wasn't the cause,of the kidneys or the stroke.
也许永远不会造成什么问题
Probably never would've been a problem.
她需要透析 而我们需要新理论
She needs dialysis,,and we need a new theory.
只有少数可能
there are only a few possibilities.
病人正在怀孕 也许是前惊厥
Patient's pregnant,,could be preeclampsia.
之前我们已经排除了--
We eliminated it before--
检查蛋白尿症和低血小板--还有什么?
check for proteinuria and low platelets--,whaelse?
循环性休克 胎儿基本上就是窃取营养,矿物质和血液的寄生虫
Hypoperfusion,the fetusis basically,a parasite stealing nutrients,minerals,blood.
对她做遥感监测
Put her on telemetry.
或者怀孕与此无关
or the pregnancy's irrelevant.
可以是感染 败血症 血栓性微血管病
Could be infection,sepsis,hus/ttp.
胆固醇栓塞也一样有可能
a cholesterol embolism is just as likely.
胆固醇小微粒落下 堵塞肾脏的小血管
Tiny particles of cholesterol rain down,and clog up the small vessels in the kidneys.
做涂片 超声检查她血管的血小板
Get a smear and ultrasound her vessels for plaque.
就这些了 应该是这五样中的一个
That's it,has to be one of those five.
要自怎样更好吗?
You know what would be even better?
就是要排除到只剩一个
If we could narrow it all the way down to one.
谢谢等待
Thank you for holding.
现在有超大量电话打入
We are experiencing extremely high call volume.
谢谢你的耐心
Thank you for your patience.
五个里一个都不是
She's 0 for 5.
要么鉴别诊断错了
Either the differential was wrong,
要么她在假装
or she's faking it.
肾衰竭一定是急性的--
Kidney failure has to be precipitated--
我们已经排除了
by one of the five we've already ruled out.
身体就那么几个原因造成肾衰
The body only has so many ways,of screwing with the kidneys.
一定是检验错了
The labs must be wrong.
我们自己做的检验 没其他人插手
We did the labs.No one else had access.
那倒不一定
That's not quite true.
你给所有的病人做这么多检查,还是只给重要的人做?
You put all your patients through this,many tests,or just the important ones?
我们要探索所有可能
We wanted to explore all the possibilities.
然后?
And?
我们排除了那些可能
We've eliminated all the possibilities.
你是说 我快死了 而你不知道为什么?
You telling me I'm dying,and you have no idea why?
你的身体运作正常
Your body is functioning properly.
那我的肾脏为什么衰竭?
So why my kidney is failing
另一个身体不正常
the other body isn'T.
胎儿有问题
There's something wrong with the fetus.
欢迎来到母体镜式反应综合症的世界
welcome to the world,of maternal mirror syndrome.
母亲身体像复杂的德国地铁系统
Mom's body is like,an intricate german metro system.
所有火车按时出发
All the trains run on time.
当她怀孕了,就像在杜塞尔多夫新开了一站
When she gets pregnant,,it's like a new station opening in dusseldorf.
新手操控 一定会出错
Bunch of rookies running things,,bound to be mistakes.
孩子在轨道上玩 触电致死
Kids play on the tracks,,get electrocuted.
不知不觉 列车拥堵在去柏林的路上
Before you know it,,trains are backed up all the way to berlin,
一群愤怒的德国佬 无车可上
and you got a bunch of,angry germans with nowhere to go.
我们都知道那对犹太人不好
And we all know that ain't good,for the jews.
这个比喻里的犹太人指谁?
Who are the jews in this metaphor?
胎儿窘迫会有几个后果
A few things can happen,to a fetus in distress.
导致流产 或产下病恹恹的婴儿
It can become a miscarriage,,still birth,very sick baby,
非常罕见的情况下 也可能是颗定时炸弹,孩子死掉时 杀死妈妈
or,on rare occasion, a time bomb,that kills mom while it's dying.
好消息是 我们治好胎儿 妈妈也会好转
Good news is,we fix the fetus,,mom gets better.
这诊断等同于买一送一
It's the diagnostic equivalent,of a two-for-one sale.
我读到的镜式反应的结果 多数不乐观
I've read the outcome of mirror syndrome,is almost always unfavorable.
不乐观...,这是医生对死婴的说法吗?
Unfavorable...,is that doctor speak for dead baby?
你以为用词好听 她就会少难过些吗?
You think she'll be less upset,if you phrase it nicely?
可以跟她说实话 她不会有事
we can tell her the truth,,that she'll be fine
只要我们诊断出那一磅重的人有什么病
as soon as we diagnose a person,who weighs about one pound.
摸不到它 不能问它哪里疼 甚至看不见
Can't touch it, can't ask where it hurts,,can't see it.
除非这儿存在可以透视人体的巨型机器
If only there existed giant machines,that could look through human skin.
镜式反应限于几个病因
Mirror syndrome has a limited number,of known causes.
心律失常 胎儿贫血,胎盘绒毛血管瘤--
Tachyarrhythmia,fetal anemia,,placental chorioangioma--
所有这些都可以医治
all of which are fixable.
就不会不容乐观 对吧?
Which would be un-unfavorable,right?
也可以是三倍13号体染色体 Ebstein畸形
Could also be trisomy 13,,ebstein's anomaly,
Galen血管的动脉瘤--
an aneurysm of galen's vein--
暴风云医生雨点般作出鉴别诊断
then dr. Storm cloud rained,all over the differential
杀死了漂亮的小宝宝
and killed the beautiful little baby.
心脏是最容易看见和治疗的,我们就从那儿开始吧
Heart's easiest to see,easiest to fix,,so let's start tre.
给妈妈做核磁共振的时候,有没有看一下胎儿的心脏?
When you did mom's mri,,did you get a look at the fetus' heart?
在视界范围内 但是不清楚
It was in the range,but blurry.
胎儿在子宫里到处动
The fetus was moving all over the place.
所以我们还要再做一次
So we need another scan.
是啊 这次还要叫胎儿躺着一动不动
Yeah,we'll just ask the fetus to lie very,,very still.
没必要
No need.
我要麻痹它
I'm going to paralyze it.
你想麻痹Emma Sloan的胎儿?
You want to paralyze emma sloan's baby?
让我猜猜 Cameron告密的?
Let me guess.Cameron?
Cameron和Chase都有顾虑
Cameron and chase both had their concerns.
不 是Cameron担心
No,cameron had concerns.
Chase只是附和她
Chase just agreed with her
因为不想失去爬上她的床的机会
because  he didn't want to lose,his all-access pass to her love rug.
他们睡在一起?
They're sleeping together?
如果睡在一起是指在清洁储藏室做爱的话
If by sleeping together you mean,having sex in the janitor's closet.
在这儿?
Here?
不 在本地高中的清洁储藏室
No,the janitor's closet at,the local high school.
虎猫 冲啊!
Go,tigercats!
你有没有拍照手机?
Do you have one of those camera phones?
我有了空间账号
'Cause I got a my space account.
等我跟你谈完就去处理他们
I will deal with them,after I deal with you.
别这样 我们再八卦一下吧
Oh,come on,let's gossip some more.
我肯定她喜欢被捆绑
I'm sure she's into bondage.
麻痹一磅重的胎儿冒险--
Paralyzing a one-pound baby risks damaging--
不麻痹 就得不到心脏清晰的核磁成像图
not paralyzing the thing risks,not getting a clean mri of its heart.
这样才能救它的命
Which we need to save its life,
借此拯救Emma的生命
which we need to do to save emma's life.
你得经过她同意
You're gonna need to get her consent.
应该不会太难
That shouldn't be too hard.
要么签字 要么你跟婴儿都死
Sign here or you and your baby both die.
我跟你一起去
I'm going with you.
很好
Oh,good.
你说过使用镇静剂有危险,这太疯狂了吧
You said sedation was risky.,This sounds insane.
注射剂进入脐带
The injection goes into the umbilical cord.
婴儿什么都感觉不到的
The baby won't feel a thing.
是胎儿
Fetus.
我是在降低期望值
I'm lowering expectations.
在这儿和约会时都有效
It works here and on dates.
利大于弊
The benefits outweigh the risks,
麻痹在一个小时后就会消失
and the paralytic will,wear off in an hour,okay?
宁愿听到自己可能死 不愿婴儿死
Must be easier to hear you might die,than your baby might die.
如果要我把自己婴儿的命运,交托给某个人
But if there's anyone,I would trust to save my baby,
那就是House医生
it would be dr. House.
胎儿
Fetus.
拿着这个
Hold this.
Cameron医生 核磁共振有结果了吗?
Dr. Cameron. The mri results back?
胎儿的心脏结构健全
The fetus' heart is structurally sound.
膀胱有问题 是普通大小的四倍
The problem's with the bladder.,It's four times normal size.
给我看看
Let me see.
膀胱过胀 占据了整个躯干,挤压着所有其它器官
Bladder's so engorged,it's taking up,the whole torso, squeezing all the other organs.
使得肺脏没有发育空间
There's no room for the lungs to develop.
也许婴儿得了下尿路梗阻
The baby has a lower urinary tract obstruction.
可以通过分流术治愈
We can fix that by inserting a shunt.
我去告诉Emma
I'll give emma the news.
你要...接管这个病例吗?
Are you...taking over the case?
House不在乎
House won't care.
他有自己的诊断
He has his diagnosis.
Cameron医生
Dr. Cameron.
跟Chase约会
Dating chase...
只能有两种结果
can only end in one of two ways.
House告诉你的?
House told you?
要么你们结婚 幸福相伴永远
You get married and live happily ever after,
要么有人受伤 再也无法共事
or somebody gets hurt,and you two can't work together,
我不得不开除一个
and I have to fire somebody.
我不愿自己的私生活给你带来这种负担
I would hate to see my personal life,become such a burden to you.
我这么说是为你好
I'm telling you this for your own good.
大概为了Chase好 你也会跟他这么说
Well,I assume you're gonna have this,same conversation with chase for his own good.
这件事上 受伤的不会是Chase
Chase isn't the one,that's gonna get hurt here.
只够一个人待
There's only room for one.
尽管我可以挤出点地方给你
Though I could scooch over.
我的社交生活属于我自己
My social life is my social life.
完全同意
Couldn't agree more.
储藏室里的私人秘密与人无关 除了...
What goes on in the privacy of a janitor's,closet is nobody's business except—
她让我结束 这就是你要的结果?
she told me to end it.,Is that what you want?
事实上我希望她会解雇你们中一个
I was actually hoping,she'd fire one of you.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
预防高空病
Trying to avoid altitude sickness.
没有直达柬埔塞的航班可乘
Couldn't score a direct flight to cambodia,
所以我决定去阿根廷,攀登声名狼藉的阿空加瓜峰
so I've decided to scale argentina's,infamous mount aconcagua.
棒极了 可惜你走不了路
Perfect,except for the fact that you can't walk.
有个莫科维印第安人部落,会背着老人...
There's a tribe of mocovi indians,who actually carry the elders—
你疯了
you're insane.
我是个疯狂的天才
I'm an insane genius.
将舱内气压降低而不是升高
Set the chamber to low pressure,instead of high.
稀薄的空气致红细胞增加,产生新的毛细管
Thinner air builds upextra red blood cells,,creates new capillaries.
在这里多呆几天,就不用去探险队营地住上六星期了
Few more days in here,,I can save myself six weeks in base camp.
核磁共振结果呢?
Where's my mri?
尿路被阻塞了
There's a blockage in the urinary tract.
简单说来 就是你的孩子不能撒尿
Simple terms,your baby can't pee.
他的膀胱肿胀 会压垮肺部
His bladder is swollen,and it's crushing his lungs.
你能治好它吗?
Well,can you fix it?
我们可以塞根细管到婴儿的膀胱
We can insert a small tube in the baby's bladder
使得尿液在孕期直接从腹部排出
that makes the urine come out straight through,his belly for the duration of the pregnancy.
膀胱减压后
The bladder decompresses,
肺就能正常发育了
and the lungs will be able to develop normally.
婴儿好转 你也会好转
When the baby gets better,you should get better.
首先我们要做个测试
First we just have to do a test to determine
看看婴儿的肾功能是否正常
whether the baby's kidneys,are functioning properly.
如果不正常会怎么样?
A-and what if they're not?
如果肾脏受损严重
If they're already too damaged,
我们就真的无能为力了
then there's really nothing we can do.
如果这次不成功 你总有机会再尝试的
If this doesn't work out,,you can always try again.
我已婚时两次流产
I miscarried twice when I was married.
离婚后 在这之前还培育过四次试管婴儿
After the divorce,I tried in vitro,,like,four times before this.
我42岁了
I'm 42.
也许是...天意不可违
Maybe it's,uh,just not meant to be.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
你想成为我 所以我想成为你
Well,you're trying to be me,,so I thought I'd try to be you.
你没我的乳沟
You don't have the cleavage for it.
但我臀部肌肉比你紧
But I havea much tighter ass.
你觉得每天都该过得像"赤裸星期四"
You think every day,should be naked thursday,
还是这是种矛盾修饰法?
or is that an oxymoron?
让我看看膀胱穿刺检验的结果
Let me see the results of the bladder tap.
还没出来
They aren't back yet.
不会有什么结论的
They're gonna be inconclusive.
你觉得我诊断错了?
You think my diagnosisis wrong?
胎儿不撒尿 则羊水应该偏少
Fetus doesn't pee,,amniotic fluid should be low.
但妈妈的羊水很正常
Mom's level is fine.
不代表我错了
Doesn't mean I'm wrong.
也许意味着我们及早发现了阻塞
Could just mean we caught,the obstruction early.
不管怎么样 你的检测都得不出什么结论
Either way,your tests,will be inconclusive.
你抽取的尿液已经,在胎儿膀胱里积了几个星期
The urine you collected has been,sitting in that fetus' bladder for weeks.
我老爸过去常说 陈尿无用
And as my pappy always said,,"stale pee is useless pee".
很好 那我再做一次穿刺
Fine,then I'll do another tap.
一样没用
Just as useless.
第一次穿刺后,存留在肾脏里的陈尿会流下来
Old urine drops down from the kidney right,after the first tap 'cause it's all backed up.
第三次膀胱穿刺才能抽到最新的尿
Bladder tap number three,will give you the freshest pee,
那时候你会发现 胎儿是否还有机会
and it's when you'll find out,if this fetus has even a fighting chance.
谢谢
Thank you.
我再做两次穿刺
I'll run two more taps.
医院院长几时起 开始做膀胱穿刺了?
Since when does the dean of medicine,run bladder taps?
她是个重要的病人
She's an important patient.
因为她搞摄影?
Because she takes pictures?
还是因为她跟你一样?
Or because she's you?
40多岁的
A woman in her 40s.
单身女人
Single.
将母性最后的渴望寄托在滴管上,(喻人工受孕)
Using a turkey baster as,a last gasp at motherhood.
你想确保她成功
And you wanna make sure she succeeds,
那么自己仍有希望
so you'll still have hope.
不客观就当不了好医生
Can't be a good doctor,if you're not objective.
这是你的病人档案
It's your file.
我不要
I don't want it.
那你干嘛说那么多?
Then why did you just say all that stuff?
为了羞辱你
To humiliate you.
- 你继续去处理这起病例,- 我不要
- You're taking the case back.,- I don't want it.
你的诊断是对的 我要休假
Your diagnosis is right.,I wanna go on vacation.
治好她你就可以去休假了
You can go on vacation,after you've cured her.
好消息
good news.
婴儿尿液里的蛋白质和电解液正常
The fetus' urinehad appropriate levels,of protein and electrolytes,
他的肾没有受损
so his kidneys aren't damaged.
我们要插入分流管
We're gonna put the shunt in,
使得婴儿的肺有更多生长空间
your baby's lungs should,have more room to grow,
你的症状也会随之消失
and your symptoms should go away.
但他出生后还要做外科手术?
But he'll still need surgery,after he's born?
到那时 去除输尿管阻塞
That's when we'll remove,the blockage in the ureter.
你会是地球上唯一一个
You'll be the only mother on the planet
庆幸孩子尿湿尿布的母亲
who appreciates the value of a wet diaper.
嗨 能把那个递给我吗?
Hey,could you hand me that?
我要用影像记录下这个超现实的过程
I'm keeping a visual memory book,of this entire surreal process,
现在是迄今为止最美妙的一刻
and this is the best part,of the story so far.
- 当然可以,- 谢谢
- Yeah,sure.,- Thanks.
这张什么时候拍的?
When did you take this?
第二次膀胱穿刺是她给我做的
Oh,she did the second bladder tap.
你留着吧
You should keep it.
不用 上班时整天都看到她
Oh,I see her all day at work,,I don't need it.
也许下了班你还想看着她
Maybe you wanna see her after work.
我说对了吧?
I'm right,right?
你看着她时流露感情
I saw the way you look at her.
谢谢
Thanks.
分流管位置正确
Shunt is in the right position.
膀胱开始减压了
The bladder's starting to decompress.
没有感染
No infection.
关于我们俩 House还说什么了吗?
Did house say anything else?,About us?
我以为你不在乎他怎么反应
I thought you didn't care,about his reaction.
想引起他的妒忌?
Trying to make him jealous?
我喜欢这份工作
I like my job.
他不能因为我们在一起就解雇你
He can't fire you just,because we're together.
我们没在一起,再说House总是为所欲为
We're not together,,and house can do whatever he wants.
我的孩子怎么样了?
How's my baby?
很好 Emma 你也一样
Doing just fine,emma.,So are you.
我的胃疼得要命
My stomach is killing me.
那不是她的胃
That's not her stomach.
能睁开眼睛吗 Emma?
Can you open your eyes,emma?
让我看看
I just need to take a look.
这是什么?
What is it?
Emma得了黄疸病
Emma's jaundiced.
她的肝脏在衰竭
Her liver's shutting dowN.
不出所料
Figures.
我刚订好去钟斯顿海峡(加拿大)的行程
I just booked my trip,to johnston strait.
我还以为你在阿根廷爬什么山呢
I thought you were climbing mount,whatever in argentina.
我得跟莫科维印第安人共同生活20年
Apparently I'd have to live with,the mocovi indians for 20 years
他们才会把我当成老人
before they'd consider me an elder.
我决定去陪逆戟鲸玩皮划艇
Decided to go kayaking with orca instead.
- 不用劳驾我的腿了,- 你现在还不能走
- No legs required.,- Can't leave yet.
肝功能衰竭,又让她的病症变得扑朔迷离
Liver failure puts her case back,in the unsolved pile.
氨基转移酶AST和ALT增加,胆红素远远超标
Increased ast,alt,,and her bilirubin's off the charts.
甚至胎儿都撒谎
Even fetuses lie.
我们根据现象诊断出下尿路梗阻
We diagnosed a lower urinary tract obstruction,because we saw one.
事实全部并非如此呢?
What if that's not the whole story?
万一这个小混蛋有所隐瞒
What if the little bugger is hiding something?
镜式反应综合征的真正原因
Real reason for the mirror syndrome.
我们是否到它床底下检查过?
Have we looked under its bed?
或看过它的日记?
Have we checked its diary?
如果问题不在泌尿生殖系统,就有可能出在心脏
If it's not gu,it could be the heart.
左心室发育不全综合症
Hypoplastic left heart syndrome.
- 心脏结构没问题,- 肺呢
- There were no structural problems.,- Lungs.
在它们发育前没法看清楚,得等上几个星期
We won't be able to get a good look,until they develop. It'll be weeks.
他坚持不了几星期
He's not gonna last weeks.
那你想怎么做?
What do you wanna do?
母体镜式反映综合症,有个万无一失的治疗方法
Maternal mirror syndrome,has one surefire cure.
分娩胎儿
Deliver the fetus.
21周大的婴儿不能分娩 会害死婴儿的
That's not viable at 21 weeks.,You'lll the baby.
是胎儿
Fetus.
语义学让你感觉更自在吗?,好象它不是人一样?
Semantics make you feel better?,Pretend it's not a person?
它会传球吗?
Can it play catch?
会吃吗?
Can it eat?
会拍出美丽动人的照片吗?
Can it take pretty pictures?
谁去跟她说?
Who wants to tell her?
膀胱肿胀不是唯一的毛病
the swollen bladder,was not the only problem.
我们不能让你继续怀着孩子,得终止妊娠
We can't leave it inside you.,We have to terminate.
不能为它分娩吗?
Well,can't you deliver him?
放进呼吸机 直到找出毛病在哪儿
Put him on a respiratory machine till--,till you figure out what's wrong.
可以
We can.
但没用
It won't matter.
胎儿至少还要两个星期才能分娩
The fetus is still at least two weeks,away from being viable.
那我再多受两个星期的苦好了
Oh,well,I'll suffer through this,for two more weeks,then.
你已经开始做肾脏透析
You're on dialysis for your kidneys.
肾脏可以等
Your kidneys can wait.
但它们不为你的肝脏服务
They don't make dialysis for your liver.
你两天都活不了
You're not gonna make it two more days.
我不会让你杀死我的孩子
I'm not gonna let you kill my baby.
它会杀死你
It's killing you.
我不要流产
I'm not having an abortion.
这不是个婴儿
It's not a baby.
而是...瘤
It's...a tumor.
我明白你想死得其所
I understand dying for a cause,
为让孩子活下来 放弃自己的性命
sacrificing your life,so your child might live.
但现在不是这情况
But that's not the choice here.
或者胎儿死 或者你们都没命
Either it dies,or you both die.
或者你治好他 我们都活下来
Or you fix him,and we both live.
我治不好它
I can't fix it.
我去安排刮宫术
I'm scheduling a d and C.
我不会同意的
I won't consent.
所以我猜你有两天时间去想办法
So i guess you have two days,to figure it out.
她的肾几乎无法复原了
Her kidneys are almost irreparable.
还得了严重的弥散性血管内凝血
She's developed severe dic.
你得强迫她终止妊娠
You have to force her to terminate.
你用皮质类固醇加速孩子的肺部发育了吗?
Did you give corticosteroids to,speed the baby's lung development?
没有 我往它胸口塞了块砧骨以阻止肺发育
No,I dropped an anvilon its chest,to prevent lung development.
我要灭绝人类 一次干掉一个胎儿
I'm trying to extinguish,the human race one fetus at a time.
再给肺点时间扩张 就能检查它内部了
Give the lungs more time to expand,so you can see inside them,
看是否是肺的问题
see if they're the problem.
我现实中的病人马上就要死了
My real patient is dying.,Very quickly.
我可不会建议她去买青香蕉,(耗时间等香蕉变黄)
Like,I wouldn't advise her to,buy any green bananas.
此时的胎儿不过是个寄生虫
The fetus is nothing more than,a parasite at this point.
移除胎儿刻不容缓
Removing it is an instant cure.
你无法让Emma从这种角度想
You're not gonna get emma,to see it that way.
她多半给婴儿取好了名字
She's probably already named the baby.
念书给他听 跟他说话
Read him books,,had conversations with him.
你说得对
You get it.
她会听你的
She'll listen to you.
不行
No.
你让这个女人拒绝流产
You let this woman refuse to terminate,
就等于协助她自杀
you're helping her commit suicide.
做为她的医生 我反对自杀
As her doctor,,my recommendation is against suicide.
如果婴儿有个医生
If the baby had a doctor,
我认为她会在夺走它生命前,穷尽一切可能
I think she would recommend exhausting,all possibilities before taking its life.
那她就是白痴
Then she'd be an idiot.
真遗憾 她是你上司
Too bad she's your boss.
万一我们最初假设错了呢?
What if our original assumption is wrong?
没有错
It isn'T.
假设她没有镜式反映综合症
If we assume,she doesn't have mirror syndrome,
那么终止怀孕对她的肝脏毫无作用
then terminating her pregnancy,isn't gonna help her liver at all.
我们已经排除了所有其它的可能
We eliminated all other possibilities.
胎儿患有水肿 生命垂危
The fetus is hydropic and in distress.
Emma的肾和肝在衰竭下去
Emma's kidneys and liver are failing.
诊断很可靠
The diagnosis is solid.
连马屁精都不同意你的话
The ass-kisser won't agree with you.
你一定错得离谱
You must be even wronger than I thought.
好吧
Fine.
那就假设她患了镜式反映综合症
Let's assume,she had mirror syndrome,
但我们治婴儿膀胱时也将它治好了
but we fixed it when,we fixed the baby's bladder.
也就是说这跟肝脏的衰竭毫无关系
That means that her failing liver,would be completely unrelated.
如果是这样 我们就能治好它
If it is,we can fix it.
也不用终止妊娠
And we don't have to terminate.
因此她认为,病人的肝脏问题实属天大的巧合
So her theory is that our patient's,liver problems were just a giant coincidence.
并不是什么惊人的巧合
It's nota surprising coincidence.
怀孕女人是有可能出现肝脏问题
Pregnant women can develop liver problems.
如果是这样
If this is the case,
我们就可以采取相应措施
we can actually do something here.
你们不认为这值得深究吗?
Don't you guys think,that's worth exploring?
妊娠急性脂肪肝会出现相同的症状
Acute fatty liver of pregnancy,would have the same symptoms.
谢谢
Thank you.
马屁精
Brown-noser.
病毒性肝炎 HELLP综合症
Viral hepatitis,hellp syndrome.
看哪 为女友挺身而出
Oh,look,sticking up for your girlfriend.
谁说骑士精神荡然无存了?
Who says chivalry's dead?
他没在开玩笑?
He's not joking?
耐心点
Be patient.
她会一一经历我们 最终染上丛林热,(电影 喻不同种族间的性吸引)
She's going through all of us,,she'll get that jungle fever eventually.
我谁都不会碰
I'm not going through anyone.
你爱他吗?
You love him?
这问题可以等到,你做完Emma的肝脏活检 对吗?
This can probably wait until,after you biopsy emma's liver,right?
不行 她的血小板太低了
we can't,her platelets are too low.
一旦刺破肝脏
Once we pierce her liver,
要阻止出血几乎不可能
it'll be next to impossible,to stop the bleeding.
从上面进去
Come in from above.
不要从腹部直接穿刺
Instead of going straight,in through her abdomen,
而是从颈部的静脉进去
go in through the veins in her neck.
颈静脉肝活检
Transjugular hepatic biopsy.
如果肝脏开始出血
If the liver starts to bleed,
也会直接流回她自己的静脉
it'll bleed right back into her own veins.
你为什么不现在就开始休假呢?
Why don't you start your vacation now?
将导丝从左边的颈内静脉通进去
Threading the guide wire through,the right internal jugular vein.
那么
So...
睡眠实验室?
the sleep lab?
你和Cameron可没睡着
You and cameron not sleeping.
这关系到底多认真?
How serious is it?
没什么
It's nothing.
她只不过想让House吃醋才这么做的
She's only doing it to make house jealous.
那你又为了什么?
Then why are you doing it?
开什么玩笑?
Are you kidding?
快到下腔静脉了
Approaching the inferior vena cava.
慢点
Slow down.
你最好别伤害她
You better not hurt her.
- 她已经有老大哥罩着了,- 是吗?
- She already has a big brother.,- She does?
显而易见 你很关心她
You obviously care very deeply about her.
我不是在保护她 我在保护我自己
I'm not protecting her,,I'm protecting myself.
Cameron心碎憔悴的时候...
A heartbroken,lovesick cameron...
比她现在更让人受不了
would be even more unbearable,than she is now.
肝静脉已经过了
You're through the hepatic vein.
下针
Firing the needle.
心率 血压大幅波动
Heart rate and bp spiking.
快把探针抽出来
Get that out of her.
胎儿的心率刚刚降到50
Fetus' heart rate just dropped to 50.
子宫开始收缩了
We've got contractions.
早产
Pre-term labor.
给她吊一针叔丁喘宁
Start a terbutaline drip.
我们用母育酚安胎 阻止了早产
We were able to control the,pre-term labor with tocolytics.
宫缩现在暂时停止了
The contraction shave subsided for now.
肝脏活检结果为阴性
And the liver biopsy was negative.
这肯定是镜式反应综合征
This is definitely mirror syndrome.
由肚子里的胎儿造成的
Her baby's doing this to her.
我们别无选择
We're out of options.
早产是由活检造成的 还是自然发生的?
Did the biopsy cause the pre-term labor,or did it happen on its own?
两者没有分别
It doesn't make a difference.
早产可能是新症状
Pre-term labor can be a new symptom.
根据新信息能得出新的诊断结果
New information gives us new theories.
难道不是这么治病的吗?
Isn't that how it works?
这个病例不同
Not in this case.
她的身体想方设法做你想阻止的事
Her body's trying to do,what you refuse to.
为了挽救自己 把胎儿赶出来
Get the baby out and save itself.
病人的转氨酶水平是正常范围的10倍
Patient's transaminases are,ten times normal.
她的肝功能即将完全停止
Her liver's on the verge of,shutting down completely.
做个TORCH检查可以--
A torch test could--
没时间再做检查了
we don't have time for more tests.
必须终止妊娠 不然她性命不保
We have to terminate or she'll die.
那我们加快速度
Then let's work faster.
希望再迫切 药效也不会加快发作
Medicine doesn't work faster,just because you hope real hard.
可以弄清楚 胎儿到底隐藏了什么
But it could help to see,what the baby's been hiding.
唯一无法检查的器官,就是胎儿的肺部
The only organ we haven't been,able to look inside is its lungs.
问题一定就出在那
The problem must be in there.
无法检查 是因为肺部还未发育完全
We haven't been able to see inside,because they're under developed.
已经给她用了皮质类固醇
We've already got her on,corticosteroids,
- 但要几个星期才会起效,- 加大皮质类固醇剂量
- but it'll take weeks for them--,- then let's drown them in corticosteroids.
多疗程治疗 加速发育
Multiple courses,,speed up their development.
对胎儿进行多疗程治疗,会抑制肾上腺的功能
Giving the baby more than one course,will suppress adrenal gland function.
对胎儿器官的发育有长期的不良影响
Have long-term adverse,effects on fetal organ development.
- 比死更糟吗?,- Emma已经用了母育酚
- Worse than death?,- emma's already on tocolytics.
多疗程治疗可能诱发肺水肿
The combination could put,her into pulmonary edema.
你只会让她死的更快
You'll just kill her faster.
只有这样才能了解胎儿的肺部状况
It's the only chance we have to,see inside those lungs.
必须让胎儿好起来 快于让Emma恶化的速度
We're just gonna have to make the baby,better faster than we make emma worse.
得了 House每天都做这样的事!
Come on, this is the kind of,thing house does every day!
House认为6个小时前 就该终止妊娠了
House thought we should,terminate six hours ago.
我自己做
I'll do it myself.
谁来阻止她?
Anybody gonna stop her?
一贯都是她阻止别人发疯的
Stopping the madness is her job.
得有人充当Cuddy 管管Cuddy了
Somebody's gotta be cuddy's cuddy.
护士!
Nurse!
- 肺水肿?,- 哪个大嘴巴说的?
- Pulmonary edema?,- Who tattled?
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
不采用皮质类固醇多疗程疗法,是有原因的
There's a reason we don't give,multiple courses of corticosteroids.
是啊 谢谢提醒
Gee, thanks.
现在该终止妊娠了
It's time to terminate.
她不想这样
That's not what she wants.
看看她
Look at her.
她不想做死胎的育婴箱
She didn't want to be,an incubator for a dead baby,
可你却硬要这样
but that's what you've done.
把喉镜给我 要不就滚出去
Either get me a laryngoscope or get out.
你是对的
you were right.
你一直都是正确的
You were all right.
现在母亲的肺部功能停止了
Now the mom's lungs are shutting down.
她的衰竭速度 比婴儿肺的发育速度快
She's dying faster than,the baby's lungs are developing.
必须停用皮质类固醇
I had to stop the corticosteroids.
你和家属谈过了吗?
Have you spoken to the family?
她唯一的亲人就是这个婴儿
The only family she's got is that baby.
他的意见偏倚
Well, he's biased.
你觉得House会怎么做?
What do you think house would do?
House想终止妊娠
House wants to terminate.
我是说如果他不终止
I mean if he didn'T.
如果他在我的位置上 他会怎么办?
If he shared my position,,what do you think he would do?
他不会像你这么痛苦
He wouldn't share your pain.
他会客观处理
He'd be objective.
是的
Right.
他会分轻重缓急
He would prioritize his problems.
他会选择终止妊娠
He'd terminate.
他不会在乎把病人的肺弄的一团糟
He wouldn't be afraid of,screwing with her lungs
还存在更严重的问题
if there was a bigger issue.
没有更严重的问题了 她需要肺
There is no bigger issue.,She needs her lungs.
现阶段未必
Not right now.
给她上了呼吸器
She's already on a respirator.
有机器替她呼吸
The machine is breathing for her.
可以对她的肺为所欲为
I can do whatever I want to her lungs.
要是你在客厅里抛接球,打碎了妈妈的花瓶
If you're playing catch in the living room,and you break your mother's vase,
你大可以继续玩下去
you may as well keep playing catch.
花瓶已经碎了
The vase is already broken.
不过这个客厅没了花瓶 无法呼吸
Yeah, except that room can't,breathe without that vase.
我要继续给她用皮质类固醇
I'm putting her back on corticosteroids.
- 起作用了,- 什么起作用了
- It worked.,- What worked?
我对胎儿肺部进行扩张
I got the baby's lungs to expand.
- 我们应该可以--,- 出租车快到了
- We should be able--,- cab's on its way.
我得赶紧收拾行李
I have to finish packing.
对于你所做所为 我有了全新的认识
I have a whole new appreciation,for what you do.
真的很难坚持己见
How hard it is to believe,when everyone around you
当身边的人都说你错了
is telling you that you're wrong.
知道他们是白痴 有帮助
Helps to know they're idiots.
你觉得我是白痴吗?
Do you think I'm an idiot?
你不够客观
You're not objective.
可你不是白痴
But you're not an idiot.
还要两个星期,胎儿的肺才能脱离母体存活
These lungs are still two weeks,away from being viable.
不过已经可以诊断了
But big enough for a diagnosis.
这些组织芽体是新长出来的
These tissue buds are new.
可能是支气管肺隔离症 或者是横膈上提
Could indicate bronchopulmonary,sequestration or diaphragmatic eventration.
我觉得是遗传性分支囊肿 或支气管闭锁
I was thinking bronchogenetic,cyst or bronchial atresia.
可能是肺损伤 先天性肺囊性腺瘤样畸形
Could be lung lesions,ccam.
会不会是--
What about--
走
move.
我以为你去度假了
I thought you started your vacation.
总得有人为老板闯的祸擦屁股
Somebody had to save,our boss' rotundus ass.
Sloan的胎儿最新MRI结果如何?
Latest mri of the sloan fetus.
肺部细小的芽体可能表明--
Small buds in the lungs could indicate--
多谢 候选答案已经有了
thanks,,got that multiple choice all worked out.
问题是 如何在a b c d及以上皆非中选择
Question is,how do we pick between,a, b, c, d and none of the above?
病房里有便携式核磁共振仪
Portable mri's in her room.
可以得到现阶段的图象--
We could get a current image--
胎儿的肺太小,核磁共振也提供不了所需细节
fetal lungs are so tiny,,an mri won't give us the details we need.
要是这病人不是蝌蚪 我们怎么办?
What would we do if,this patient were not just a tadpole?
比如说它是个活生生的人
Say it was an actual person.
他是...个人
He...is a person.
谢谢你参与我们
Thanks for playing along.
假设这是一个一磅重的成年人
Pretend it's a one-pound adult.
别管母体 子宫和胎盘
Forget the mom,forget the womb,,the placenta.
怎么才能更清楚地查看肺的内部?
How would we get a better,look at what's in the lungs?
做食道超声图
Transe sophageal echo.
进不了胎儿的食道
Can't access its esophagus.
高分辨率CT诊断可以让我们更清楚的—
High-resolution ct could,give us a clearer—
一磅重的婴儿受不了那么大的辐射
too much radiation for a,one-pound person.
你不能什么都否决 Chase
You can't just shoot,everything down,chase.
你又不是我 合作
You're not me.Collaborate.
接下来做肺通气灌注扫描
A ventilation perfusion scan,would be next.
怎么让胎儿吸入放射性同位素?
How do we get a fetus to breathe,in a radioactive isotope?
白痴
Idiot.
如果它是个人 没有其他选择的话
If it were really a person,and we had no other options,
可以做探测手术
we'd do an exploratory surgery.
剖开胸 看个明白
Cut into its chest and have,a look around.
我们就这么做吧
Let's do that.
是你要坚持把它当人看
You're the one who insists,we treat it like a person.
等我做完 会把它放回去的
I'll put it back when I'm done.
我又来了
Me again.
你友好的邻家挤肚子人
Your friendly neighborhood belly-squirter.
我们要进行胎儿外科治疗
We're gonna doopen fetal surgery.
剖开子宫 取出胎儿看个究竟
We open the uterus,,cut out the fetus so we can look around.
我知道你不能说话 那么
I know you can't talk,so
要是你同意 给个目瞪口呆的表情
I need you to look petrified,if you consent.
我们不会割断脐带
The umbilical cord won't be cut.
手术中
During surgery,
你的身体基本等同于胎儿的心肺机
your body will basically serve,as the baby's heart-lung machine.
我们会找到问题治好它
We find what's wrong and we fix it.
尽我们所能
If we can.
有利用价值时 别降低期望值
Don't lower expectations,if you want them to do something.
她有权了解将经历的一切
She should know what she's facing.
手术过程非常危险
This is incredibly dangerous.
会危及你和宝宝的生命
It risks both your lives.
建议这么做仅仅是因为
The only reason why we're suggesting it
没有别的方法了
is because there's nothing else we can do.
你们都是来做胎儿手术的?
You all here for the fetal surgery?
这可太挤了
We are way over capacity.
留意私人空间
Mind each other's personal space.
手术室里有各种锋利的器具
There are sharp implements in the room.
就像这个
Like this one.
子宫暴露
uterus is fully exposed.
进入了
And we're in.
开始抽羊水
Start draining the amniotic fluid.
你从没从啤酒桶底吸过啤酒吗?
Have you never sucked beer,out the bottom of a keg?
- 你在哪读的大学啊?,- 给我
- Where'd you go to college?,- Gimme that.
把脉搏血氧计粘到手掌上
Affix the pulse ox to the palm.
House.
House
抱歉
Sorry.
我刚想起忘了录异形
I just realized I forgot to tivo alien.
胎儿心率正常,数据稳定
fetal heart rate good,,stats are stable.
放好胎儿 开始切割
Position him for the incision.
好的 我看到三处明显的损伤
all right,,I see three well-defined lesions.
肯定是先天性肺囊性腺瘤样畸形
It's definitely ccam.
我应该能切除他们
I should be able to resect them.
是母体 心室颤动
It's the mom.She's in v-fib.
充电
Charging.
离手
Clear!
离手了
I'm clear.
好像是心脏无收缩,电击不起作用
Looks like asystole,,paddling's not gonna do anything.
是良性的心律失常!再来一次
It's fine v-fib!I'm going again.
离手
Clear!
母婴都快不行了 钳子
We're gonna lose them both.Clamp.
不是手术造成的 是胎儿
The surgery's not doing this to her,,the fetus is.
让开 House 我要再来一次
Step away,house,I'm going again.
救她唯一的方法 就是拖她不断下沉的锚
The only way to save her is to,cut away the anchor holding her down.
你要这么做 我就电死你
You keep going,,you're gonna get electrocuted.
离手!
clear!
再来一次 准备就绪!
Going again.Clear!
心率恢复正常
Heart rate's returning to normal.
继续叶切除术
Continue with the lobectomy.
那么我的肾 肝 肺都没问题了?
So my kidneys,,liver,and lungs are all fine?
就这么好了?
Just like that?
就这么好了
Just like that.
太神奇了
That's amazing.
你宝宝的金发才神奇
What's amazing is how blond,your baby's hair is.
我的宝宝?
My baby?
就是你肚子里试图害死你的小东西
You know,the thing in your belly,that tried to kill you.
你以前从没叫过他宝宝
You've never called him a baby before.
疼吗?
Any pain?
还好 都受得了
Nothing I can't deal with.
除了小便大便洗澡 否则不要起床
You can only get out of bed to pee,,poo,or shower.
还有严禁性生活 不要再跟我调情
And absolutely no sex,,so stop flirting with me.
对不起
Sorry.
那么真的治好了 他会是...
So this really worked?He'll be...
正常的吗?
normal?
你要觉得出生两次正常 那就正常
if you call being born twice normal.
嘿 谢谢你
Hey, thank you.
不用谢我
Don't thank me.
我本来打算牺牲小孩的
I would a killed the kid.
想去吃点东西吗?
Wanna grab a bite?
马上来
In a minute.
Emma让我把相机带过去
Emma asked me to bring up her camera.
我陪你去
I'll walk you.
她什么时候给你拍了这张照片?
When'd she take this picture of you?
你看起来非常...
You look so...
我在微笑
I'm smiling.
我笑起来很帅
I have a nice smile.
不是 我从没看过你这个样子
No, I've never seen you like this.
她让你...
She got you to...
神采焕发
glow.
你当时在做什么?
What were you doing?
她对你说了什么?
What'd she say to you?
我一直都神采焕发
I always glow.
House.
House
你来看看这个
Need you to take a look at something.
- 我下班了,- 打开就是了
- I'm off the clock.,- Just open it.
去与温哥华岛的头等舱机票
First class ticket to vancouver island.
糟了 拿错信封了!
Shoot! It's the wrong envelope.
- 我觉得很棒,- 是吧?
- I think it's great.,- Yeah?
谁不喜欢加拿大人啊?
Who doesn't like canadians?
这是大好事 你试着去生活
It's big.You're--,you're trying to have a life.
试着享受
You're trying to enjoy yourself.
你不用道歉
You didn't need to apologize.
我没打算道歉 我说过为什么我--
I'm not, I told you why I'm--
你搞砸了
you screwed up.
我救了一条命 我救了两条命
I saved a life.I saved two lives.
你放任自己的母性本能
You let your maternal instinct,get the best of you
差点害死两条人命
and nearly killed two people.
这种病例 如果终止妊娠,母体存活率是百分之百
Case like this,you terminate,,mom lives 10 times out of 10.
按你的做法 九成九母婴都会死掉
You do what you did,mom and,baby both die 9.9 times out of 10.
有些时候 0.1大于9.9
Sometimes .1 is bigger than 9.9.
不可能 0.1更小
No, it's smaller.
整整小9.8
Exactly 9.8 smaller.
一直是 将来也是
Always is,always will be.
起码 对Emma来说不是
Well, not for emma.
对她儿子来说也不是
And not for her son.
走远点
Now go away.
好好享受
And be happy.
*Are you alright?*,*你还好吗?*
*Are you alright?*
*All of a sudden you went away*,*你突然离去*
*All of a sudden you went away*
*are you alright?*,*你还好吗?*
*are you alright?*
*I hope you come back around some day*,*多希望你会回来*
*I hope you come back around some day*
*Are you alright?*,*你还好吗?*
*are you alright?*
*I haven't seen you in a real long time*,*好久不见*
*I haven't seen you in a real long time*
*Are you alright?*,*你还好吗?*
*are you alright?*
*Could you give me some kind of sign?*,*请给我点讯息?*
*Could you give me some kind of sign?*
*Are you alright?*,*你还好吗?*
*Are you alright?*
*Are you sleeping through the night?*,*夜晚能否入睡?*
*Are you sleeping through the night?*
*Do you have someone to hold you tight?*,*有没有人紧拥着你?*
Do you have someone to hold you tight?
*Do you have someone to hang out with?*,*有没有人陪伴你?*
*Do you have someone to hang out with?*
*Do you have someone to hug and kiss you?*,*有没有人拥吻你?*
*Do you have someone to hug and kiss you?*
*Hug and kiss you hug and kiss you*,*拥吻你*
*Hug and kiss you hug and kiss you*
*Are you alright?*,*你还好吗?*
*are you alright?*
*嗨*
*Hey*